Rockwell Kent
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Alphabetical Files, circa 1900-1971, undated, Series 1:; (Reels 5153-5249, 5256, 5740-5741)
  - Prima Theatrical Co., 1946 (Reel 5224, Frame 922-925)
  - Prime, May, 1945, undated (Reel 5224, Frame 927-934)
  - Primus, Pearl, 1945-1948 (Reel 5224, Frame 935-961)
    (letters [mostly illegible due to water damage], greeting cards, programs of Primus dance performance, and newspaper article about her)
  - Princeton University, 1941-1947, 1960-1963 (Reel 5224, Frame 962-993)
  - Print, 1941 (Reel 5224, Frame 994-1004)
  - Print Club (Cleveland, Ohio), 1933 (Reel 5224, Frame 1005-1016)
    (correspondence concerning edition of Mountain Climber published by the club)
  - The Print Club (Philadelphia) (see also: Philadelphia Print Club), 1941 (Reel 5224, Frame 1017-1019)
  - The Print Collector's Quarterly, 1939, 1949-1950 (Reel 5224, Frame 1020-1026)
  - Print Council of America, 1960 (Reel 5224, Frame 1027-1034)
  - The Print Rooms (see: Furman, Erwin) (Reel 5224)
  - Pritt, Mr., 1952 (Reel 5224, Frame 1035-1037)
  - Processing Sheets, 1947 (Reel 5224, Frame unfilmed)
    (dairy business statistics)
  - Professional Art Quarterly (see: Duggar, Ben) (Reel 5224)
  - Program, 1941-1942 (Reel 5224, Frame 1038-1044)
  - Progress Publishing Company, 1939 (Reel 5224, Frame 1045-1048)
  - Progressive Citizens of America, 1947 (Reel 5224, Frame 1049-1053)
  - Progressive Librarians Council, 1941 (Reel 5224, Frame 1054-1104)
    (correspondence concerning arrangements for radio broadcast and publication of Kent's speech; letters in support of council president Philip Keeny's ambition to become director of Cleveland Public Library; see also: Radio Addresses)
  - Progressive Party, 1948-1965 (Reel 5224, Frame 1105-1197)
  - Promoting Enduring Peace, 1951-1965 (Reel 5224, Frame 1198-1209)
  - The Protestant, 1948 (Reel 5224, Frame 1210-1217)
  - Protestantism Answers Hate, 1941 (Reel 5224, Frame 1218-1222)
  - Provident Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1958 (Reel 5224, Frame 1223-1227)
  - Provisional Citizens Committee to Aid Letter Shop Workers, 1941 (Reel 5224, Frame 1228-1237)
  - Proxies, 1944 (Reel 5224, Frame unfilmed)
    (relating to investments)
  - Public Broadcasting Environment Center, 1970 (Reel 5224, Frame 1238-1243)
  - Public Service Commission, 1938-1939, 1949 (Reel 5224, Frame 1244-1309)
    (correspondence with lawyers, elected officials, etc., concerning complaints about fare structure and condition of Delaware and Hudson railway cars; legal papers dismissing the complaint)
  - Public Use of Arts Committee, 1938-1939, undated (Reel 5224, Frame 1310-1348)
    (correspondence about art for decoration of subway stations, invitation to serve on committee, arrangements for Kent radio address publicizing City-Wide Children's Arts Festival; texts of interview and speech)
  - Publications Contributed to, 1940-1970 (Reel 5224, Frame 1349-1522)
    (correspondence with authors and editors concerning book reviews, introductions, and articles by Kent for publication in books, exhibition catalogs, newspapers, and magazines relating to art, politics, the USSR, and other subjects; reproduction permissions)
  - Publications Contributed to, cont. (Reel 5225, Frame 3-1531)
  - Publications Contributed to, cont. (Reel 5226, Frame 3-164)
  - Publicity, 1941, undated (Reel 5226, Frame 165-185)
  - Publishers, 1968-1969 (Reel 5226, Frame 186-225)
  - The Publisher's Weekly, 1941 (Reel 5226, Frame 226-228)
  - Puerto Rican Mural, 1937-1938, undated (Reel 5226, Frame 229-400)
    (correspondence concerning controversy over Kent mural in Post Office Department, Washington, D.C., depicting delivery of Eskimo-language message to the people of Puerto Rico and interpreted as supporting Puerto Rican independence; undated manuscript of "Let Us Change Chiefs," an article by Kent about the mural controversy; see also: Post Office Murals; Post Office Murals Controversy; and Quinn, Tom)
  - Puerto Rico, 1936-1957 (Reel 5226, Frame 401-591)
    (correspondence, 1936-1944, about political and labor conditions in Puerto Rico, civil rights and political prisoners, and Puerto Rican nationalism; correspondence, 1956-1957, with friends in Puerto Rico and plans for visiting)
  - Pulitzer, Ralph, 1922, 1927-1929, undated (Reel 5226, Frame 592-625)
  - Pulitzer, Seward W. (Pully), 1946-1947 (Reel 5226, Frame 626-630)
  - The Pullman Company, 1942-1946 (Reel 5226, Frame 631-644)
  - Puma, Fernando, 1944 (Reel 5226, Frame 645-648)
  - Punsky, Frania, 1941 (Reel 5226, Frame 649-653)
  - Purdue University, 1955 (Reel 5226, Frame 654-657)
  - Purdy, James, 1961 (Reel 5226, Frame 658-661)
  - Pushman vs. New York Graphic Society, 1941 (Reel 5226, Frame 662-679)
    (correspondence concerning artists' publication rights)
  - Putnam, George P., 1919-1956, 1965 (Reel 5226, Frame 680-934)
    (correspondence concerning Rockwell Kent, Inc., publication of books written and/or illustrated by Kent; royalty statements; see also: Brewer & Warren, Inc.)
  - Putnam, Israel, Sr., 1941 (Reel 5226, Frame 935-938)
  - Putnam, Peg, 1956-1957 (Reel 5226, Frame 939-943)
  - Putnam, Samuel, 1941 (Reel 5226, Frame 944-949)
  - Putnam's Bookstore, 1946 (Reel 5226, Frame 950-954)
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1941-1942 (Reel 5226, Frame 955-973)
  - Pynson Printers Incorporated, 1927-1940 (Reel 5226, Frame 974-1572)
    (correspondence about design details and specifications for illustrated books, bookplates, and other Kent work; founding of colophon magazine; invoices with some samples of completed work; see also: Adler, Elmer)
  - Pynson Printers Incorporated, cont. (Reel 5227, Frame 3-339)
  - P, Unidentified and Illegible (Reel 5227, Frame 340-346)
    (Guido and Grace P., undated; Horace Pecu[?], 1948; Rosamund, 1970)
  - Quayle, Bruce, 1957 (Reel 5227, Frame 347-349)
  - The Queen Elizabeth, 1970 (Reel 5227, Frame 350-352)
  - Queen, Ellery, undated (Reel 5227, Frame 353-356)
  - Quinn, Tom, 1941 (Reel 5227, Frame 357-363)
    (design and installation of murals for U.S. Post Office Department, Washington, D.C.; correspondence, press releases, and clippings regarding controversy over Eskimo-language message incorporated in the mural that was interpreted as support for Puerto Rican independence; see also: Post Office Murals; Post Office Murals Controversy; Puerto Rican Mural)
  - Rabin and Krueger Gallery, 1954 (Reel 5227, Frame 364-369)
  - Rabinowitz, Clara, 1910, 1915 (Reel 5227, Frame 370-391)
  - Rabinowitz, N., 1933-1939 (Reel 5227, Frame 392-414)
    (concerning purchases of art supplies)
  - Rackley, Mildred, 1941-1942 (Reel 5227, Frame 415-420)
  - Radical Groups--Communist Party and Activities, 1935-1937 (Reel 5227, Frame 421-516)
    (correspondence regarding contributions, request for cover illustration and discussion of symbolism of final design, and invitations to speak at or attend events)
  - Radical Groups--Fascism--American League Against War and Fascism, 1936-1937 (Reel 5227, Frame 517-560)
    (inquiries about magazine cover designs, lectures, invitations to events, form letters and other printed matter)
  - Radical Groups--Germany--Guild for German Cultural Freedom; Committee for Anti-Nazi Literature, etc., 1936-1937 (Reel 5227, Frame 561-591)
    (requests for sponsorship and invitations to speak)
  - Radical Groups--Political Prisoners, National Committee for the Defense of, 1936-1938, undated (Reel 5227, Frame 592-841)
    (correspondence and printed matter, mainly about Brazil and fund raising)
  - Radical Groups--Russia--Soviet Russia Today, 1936-1937 (Reel 5227, Frame 842-865)
    (correspondence concerning article and drawings for the magazine; see also: Soviet Russia Today)
  - Radical Groups--Sharecroppers, 1936-1940, undated (Reel 5227, Frame 866-960)
    (correspondence about plight of southern agricultural laborers and their need to unionize, request for Kent to design stamp for the cause, and film about sharecroppers; letters from Lee Hays concerning his progress as a writer, with copy of a short story; printed matter)
  - Radical Groups--Spain--Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1936-1938 (Reel 5227, Frame 961-1096)
    (correspondence about activities of Artists and Writers Committee, fund raising, invitations to speak, requests to design logo; form letters; clippings; see also: Spanish Causes)
  - Radical Groups--Various Assorted, 1936-1938 (Reel 5227, Frame 1097-1204)
    (includes correspondence with American League to Abolish Capital Punishment, Bill of Rights Poster Contest, Gallup Civil Rights Commission, Federal Arts Committee, and Federal Writers' Project)
  - Radio Addresses, 1941-1960 (Reel 5227, Frame 1205-1358)
    (text of speech to Progressive Librarians Council and resulting fan mail, 1941; scripts for campaign speeches, 1946 or 1948; correspondence concerning arrangements for broadcasts, and texts of remarks on peace, 1959-1960; see also: Progressive Librarians Council; and Speeches)
  - Radio Corporation of America, 1930 (Reel 5227, Frame 1359-1366)
  - Raffles, 1968 (Reel 5227, Frame 1367-1369)
  - Rahr, Guido, 1943-1950, 1966 (Reel 5227, Frame 1370-1461)
    (correspondence about centennial history of Rahr Malting Co., written and illustrated by Kent, and technical details of its printing; see also: Hinrichs, Hans; History of Manitowoc Co. Rahr Family; and To Thee)
  - Rail Travel Credit Agency, 1948-1949 (Reel 5227, Frame unfilmed)
    (credit card contract and related correspondence)
  - Rainey, Pat, 1951-1954, 1958, undated (Reel 5227, Frame 1462-1511)
  - Rajappan, P., 1962 (Reel 5227, Frame 1512-1516)
  - Ramsey, Carl T., 1958-1959 (Reel 5227, Frame 1517-1523)
  - Random House, 1928-1959, 1970 (Reel 5227, Frame 1524-1559)
    (correspondence concerning Kent-illustrated books published by Random House, ideas for future projects, payments and royalties, and commissions to design insignia and bookplate)
  - Random House, cont. 1928-1959, 1970 (Reel 5228, Frame 3-253)
  - Rantz, Berta, 1959 (Reel 5228, Frame 254-256)
  - Rapid Blue Print Co. (see: Davis, Henry R.) (Reel 5228)
  - Rapp, Hilde, 1946 (Reel 5228, Frame 257-259)
  - Rasmussen, Knud, 1929-1931 (Reel 5228, Frame 260-324)
    (correspondence regarding translations of Greenland sagas, and plans for Kent voyage to Greenland; see also: Denmark Correspondence)
  - Rationing--Farm Machinery, 1944 (Reel 5228, Frame unfilmed)
  - Rationing Correspondence (see also: Fuel Coupons), 1944-1945 (Reel 5228, Frame unfilmed)
  - Raus, Milton, 1947 (Reel 5228, Frame 325-327)
  - Robert Raven Rehabilitation Committee, 1950 (Reel 5228, Frame 328-331)
  - Raymond and Raymond Incorporated, 1937-1940 (Reel 5228, Frame 332-371)
    (about reproduction of Mt. Equinox and Winter, Monhegan)
  - Raymond & Whitcomb Company, 1926 (Reel 5228, Frame 372-374)
  - Raymond, Frank Jo, 1941, 1950, 1952 (Reel 5228, Frame 375-382)
  - Read, H. O., 1926-1931 (Reel 5228, Frame 383-417)
  - Read, Mary, 1937 (Reel 5228, Frame 418-425)
  - Readers Digest, 1946 (Reel 5228, Frame 426-428)
  - Real Estate (Farms for Sale), 1939 (Reel 5228, Frame 429-434)
    (offer to sell property to Kent)
  - Real, James, 1962-1963 (Reel 5228, Frame 435-443)
  - Reality: A Journal of Artists' Opinions, 1954 (Reel 5228, Frame 444-448)
  - Rebalbuto, L. A., 1942 (Reel 5228, Frame 777-785)
  - Rebentisch, Martha R., 1952 (Reel 5228, Frame 449-452)
  - Reber, Alma (Mrs. Jean Loomis Reeber), 1948 (Reel 5228, Frame 453-458)
  - Receipts--Contracts, etc., 1928-1931 (Reel 5228, Frame 459-462)
    (passenger car registration, check stubs from publishers)
  - Red Cross 1944 War Fund of Greater New York, Artists for Victory Division, 1944 (Reel 5228, Frame 463-467)
  - Carroll Reed Ski Shops, 1952 (Reel 5228, Frame 473-476)
  - Reed, Carolyn H., undated (Reel 5228, Frame 477-480)
  - Reed, Gordon and Kate [aunt] (see also: Banff, Canada), 1927-1959 (Reel 5228, Frame 481-547)
  - Reed, Lawrence, 1942-1966 (Reel 5228, Frame 548-609)
    (correspondence with collector of Kentiana who requested help in selling his collection)
  - Reed, [illegible], undated (Reel 5228, Frame 468-472)
  - Reeves, Ruth, 1948-1965 (Reel 5228, Frame 610-673)
    (correspondence about hiring a Reeves student to assist Kent, Artists Equity Association, mutual friends, Kent on relation of design to literary expression, Reeves's travels to India, and gift of Kent Collection to the USSR; article about Reeves)
  - Refregier, Anton, 1957-1970 (Reel 5228, Frame 674-776)
  - Rehn, Frank K. M., 1927-1929 (Reel 5228, Frame 786-794)
    (includes receipt for sale of painting and shipping arrangements)
  - Reiner, Mr., undated (Reel 5228, Frame 795-798)
  - Reingold, Morris, 1956 (Reel 5228, Frame 799-804)
  - Reiser, Paul, 1966-1967 (Reel 5228, Frame 805-814)
  - Reiter, Dr. Samuel, 1948 (Reel 5228, Frame 815-819)
  - Relief in Spain, 1937-1939 (Reel 5228, Frame 820-833)
    (mainly form letters from American Red Cross)
  - Rennell, Martin and Florence, 1941, 1943 (Reel 5228, Frame 834-848)
  - Replies from Art Teachers to Text Book Questionnaire, 1941 (Reel 5228, Frame 849-911)
    (form letter to instructors of college students training to be art teachers, seeking comments about Kent's proposed text book; sample table of contents and replies; see also: Text Book)
  - Reproductions (Requests for Permission) (see also: Permissions), 1941-1942 (Reel 5228, Frame 912-938)
  - Resika, A., 1962, 1965 (Reel 5228, Frame 939-942)
  - Resist, 1967 (Reel 5228, Frame 943-945)
  - Ressinger, Paul M., 1941 (Reel 5228, Frame 946-952)
  - Reyes, Guadalupe, 1941 (Reel 5228, Frame 953-956)
  - Reymond, Frank, 1965 (Reel 5228, Frame 957-961)
  - Reynolds, James, 1942 (Reel 5228, Frame 962-968)
  - Reynolds, Julia C., undated (Reel 5228, Frame 969-971)
  - Rhodes, Clayton E., 1954 (Reel 5228, Frame 972-975)
  - Rhythm: A Journal for the Promotion of the Four Arts, 1955 (Reel 5228, Frame 976-978)
  - Rice, Anna T., 1945 (Reel 5228, Frame 979-982)
  - Rice, Shepherd, 1962, 1968-1970 (Reel 5228, Frame 983-993)
  - Richards, G. Thayer, 1940 (Reel 5228, Frame 994-999)
  - Rich's, Inc., 1941-1942 (Reel 5228, Frame 1000-1005)
  - Rideout, Patricia M., 1947 (Reel 5228, Frame 1006-1010)
  - Rie, Paul, 1950 (Reel 5228, Frame 1011-1013)
  - The Right to Travel Exhibition, 1955 (Reel 5228, Frame 1014-1137)
    (correspondence concerning arrangements and publicity for the show, a fund raiser intended to defray Kent's legal expenses for passport lawsuit; clippings related to passport problems)
  - Ripley, A. Crooks, 1935-1947 (Reel 5228, Frame 1138-1200)
    (correspondence with an English fan)
  - Ritz Tower Hotel, 1942 (Reel 5228, Frame 1201-1203)
  - Rivera Appeal, 1957 (Reel 5228, Frame 1204-1290)
    (Diego Rivera's letter "to Rockwell Kent and all artists and men of culture" calling for an end to nuclear weapons; correspondence with National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, William Gropper, Rivera, and Norman Cousins about how to bring widespread attention to the appeal; text of address by Pablo Neruda to World Council of Peace, Ceylon, June 1957)
  - Rivers, Myra, 1939 (Reel 5228, Frame 1291-1294)
  - Robare, Louis P. and Nancy, 1951-1960, 1968 (Reel 5228, Frame 1295-1309)
  - Robbins, Rachel, 1955 (Reel 5228, Frame 1310-1312)
  - Roberts, Holland (see also: American Russian Institute), 1951, 1957-1958 (Reel 5228, Frame 1313-1321)
  - Roberts, Ronnie & Richard, 1962-1963 (Reel 5228, Frame 1322-1326)
  - Robeson, Paul, 1942-1953 (Reel 5228, Frame 1327-1410)
    (includes letter of congratulation on Othello, review, and theater program; form letters concerning fund raising for Council on African Affairs; invitation to visit Kent, and requests for Robeson to appear at or support various events sponsored by civil rights or political organizations; birth announcements)
  - Robeson Process Co., 1946 (Reel 5228, Frame 1411-1413)
  - Robin, Eva, 1936 (Reel 5228, Frame 1414-1416)
  - Robinson, Earl, 1965 (Reel 5228, Frame 1417-1423)
  - Robinson, Ione, 1945-1970 (Reel 5228, Frame 1424-1519)
    (outline of a book and correspondence about possibilities for collaboration; also, her financial and medical problems, and advice from Kent)
  - Robinson, Joseph, 1939, 1950 (Reel 5228, Frame 1520-1524)
  - Robinson, Reid, 1949 (Reel 5228, Frame 1525-1533)
  - Robinson Travel, 1946-1950 (Reel 5228, Frame 1534-1563)
  - Robinson Travel, cont. (Reel 5229, Frame 3-32)
  - Roche Advertising Co., 1926-1930 (Reel 5229, Frame 33-49)
    (correspondence concerning drawing for the Chicago Tribune)
  - Roche, Margrit Andresen, 1938 (Reel 5229, Frame 50-114)
    (letters to Kent, American Artists Congress and the Artists Union, with "Purpose of the Free Lance Artists' Mutual Enterprises and Allied Creative Enterprises," a plan for a federation of artists' cooperatives)
  - Rochester, Charles E., 1941 (Reel 5229, Frame 115-118)
  - Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1926 (Reel 5229, Frame 119-121)
  - Rockwell, Norman, 1941, 1949-1952 (Reel 5229, Frame 122-130)
  - Roe, Wellington, 1941-1945, undated (Reel 5229, Frame 131-315)
    (correspondence about request to write introduction to a book by Art Young and Roe, activities of the National Committee for Peoples' Rights, account of Roe's dismissal from civilian position with U.S. Navy for previous political activities, compulsory military training, Roe's work for Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, and Kent drawings for some of its publications)
  - Roerich Academy of Arts, 1941 (Reel 5229, Frame 317-321)
  - Roerich Museum, 1929-1930, 1941 (Reel 5229, Frame 322-341)
    (request for biographical information and a photo to include in upcoming book on leaders of American artistic and cultural life, article proposing creation of international peace flag, and catalog of exhibition from the collection of George S. Hellman that included a painting by Kent)
  - Roerich, Nicholas, 1945 (Reel 5229, Frame 342-346)
  - Roerich Pact and Banner of Peace Committee, 1946 (Reel 5229, Frame 347-350)
  - Rogers, Bruce, 1946, 1950 (Reel 5229, Frame 351-365)
  - Rogers, Henry Geer, undated, 1964 (Reel 5229, Frame 366-371)
  - J. & J. Rogers Company, 1936, 1959-1961 (Reel 5229, Frame 372-385)
  - Rogers, John C., 1954 (Reel 5229, Frame 386-390)
  - Rogers, Spaulding, 1958 (Reel 5229, Frame 391-395)
  - Rogers, Sydney, 1938, 1945 (Reel 5229, Frame 396-406)
  - Rogge, O. John and Wanda, 1948-1950 (Reel 5229, Frame 407-430)
  - Rohr, Eugene, 1945, 1947 (Reel 5229, Frame 431-435)
  - Rojankovski, Feodor, 1944-1945 (Reel 5229, Frame 436-441)
  - Romano, Emanuel, 1941, 1943 (Reel 5229, Frame 442-446)
  - Romanoff, Michael, 1930-1936 (Reel 5229, Frame 447-489)
    (correspondence about money owed to Kent, and Romanoff's impersonation of Kent; news clippings)
  - Romas, Yakov and Alyosha, 1964-1966, undated (Reel 5229, Frame 490-523)
  - Rome, Carolyn, undated (Reel 5229, Frame 524-527)
  - Roos, Delmar G. (Barney), 1943-1946 (Reel 5229, Frame 528-543)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. and Eleanor, 1938-1945 (Reel 5229, Frame 544-583)
    (letters to the president regarding American policy in Japan, praising speech at the Museum of Modern Art and emphasizing importance of Fine Arts Division of WPA, supporting the release of Earl Browder and Harry Bridges, protesting against FBI investigator's questions concerning Soviet students' Christmas visit to Kent home; letter of condolence to Eleanor Roosevelt upon the death of her husband)
  - Roosevelt, Truman, Eisenhower, 1945 (Reel 5229, Frame unfilmed)
    (PM and Daily Worker issues reporting the death and funeral of FDR, and inauguration of Truman)
  - Roper, Elmo, 1949 (Reel 5229, Frame 584-587)
  - Rose, William, 1961 (Reel 5229, Frame 588-590)
  - Roselius, Ludwig, 1917-1928 (Reel 5229, Frame 591-626)
    (letters and clippings from Bulgaria's general counsel to Germany)
  - Rosemarie de Paris, Inc., 1949 (Reel 5229, Frame 627-633)
  - Rosen, Charles (see: Creative Art) (Reel 5229)
  - Rosen, Dr., 1960 (Reel 5229, Frame 680-682)
  - Rosen, Helen and Sam, undated (Reel 5229, Frame 634-639)
  - Rosen, Herbert, 1956-1957 (Reel 5229, Frame 640-679)
    (correspondence concerning arrangements for Nord Co. to publish Kent drawings on Christmas cards; see also: Nord Co.)
  - Rosenberg, James N. and Bessie, 1927-1970 (Reel 5229, Frame 683-1410)
    (correspondence with artist friend who was also Kent's attorney, concerning: purchase of property, Kent's complaint against Delaware and Hudson, problems with publishers, refugees in Dominican Republic, investments, Kent's American Labor Party campaign, politics, revision of wills of Rockwell and Sally, criticism of Metropolitan Museum, gifts and purchases of art by Rosenberg, civil rights, and anti-Semitism; also gallery announcements of Rosenberg exhibitions)
  - Rosenberg, Vivian and Irving, 1957-1963 (Reel 5229, Frame 1411-1448)
  - Rosenfeld, Ernest, 1936 (Reel 5229, Frame 1449-1451)
  - Rosenfeld, Kurt, 1943 (Reel 5229, Frame 1452-1455)
  - Rosengren, Mrs. Frank, 1936-1938 (Reel 5229, Frame 1456-1471)
    (correspondence regarding bookplate design, and exhibition of Kent prints in Rosengren's bookstore)
  - Ross, Marion Sheila, 1950-1960 (Reel 5229, Frame 1472-1490)
  - Rotary Club, 1939 (Reel 5229, Frame 1491-1507)
    (correspondence concerning speaking engagement at Rotary Club in Glens Falls, N.Y., and reply to its request for further information about the American League for Peace and Democracy)
  - Rothman, Walter, 1941 (Reel 5229, Frame 1508-1511)
  - Rothschild, Lincoln, 1968 (Reel 5229, Frame 1512-1514)
  - Rothschild, Myron, 1939, 1949 (Reel 5229, Frame 1515-1522)
  - Rouse, Blair, 1948 (Reel 5229, Frame 1523-1526)
  - Royal Society of Arts, 1946 (Reel 5229, Frame 1527-1530)
  - Royalties, Dividends, etc. (Deposits), 1940-1946 (Reel 5229, Frame unfilmed)
    (mainly banking records, some receipts, check stubs, and itemized statements of royalties)
  - Rubenstein, Dr. H. J., 1941 (Reel 5229, Frame 1531-1536)
  - Rubenstein, John Bendix, 1941 (Reel 5229, Frame 1537-1541)
  - Rubin, Bill and Rose, 1961-1962 (Reel 5229, Frame 1542-1546)
  - Rubin, Louis S., 1960 (Reel 5229, Frame 1547-1551)
  - Rubin, Mr., 1940 (Reel 5229, Frame 1552-1554)
  - Rubinstein, Annette, 1958, 1960, 1963 (Reel 5230, Frame 3-23)
  - Rudabarg, Anna and Stanley, 1966 (Reel 5230, Frame 24-28)
  - Rudhyar, D., undated (Reel 5230, Frame 29-77)
    ("An Introduction to the Mysteries of Space," by D. Rudhyar, poet, philosopher, and composer; series of poems, "New York Summer," and letter of congratulations to Kent on his appointment as editor of Creative Art, with offer to contribute articles)
  - Ruggles, Carl, undated, 1913-1928, 1966, 1969 (Reel 5230, Frame 78-208)
    (letters including thanks to Kent for opera ideas and mention of Stokowski; discussion of Ruggles's work and Kent's activities)
  - H. I. Ruggles & Company, 1953 (Reel 5230, Frame 209-211)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1940-1941 (Reel 5230, Frame 212-218)
  - Rumania, 1959-1961 (Reel 5230, Frame 219-471)
    (correspondence with friends and officials of the Rumanian Institute for Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries, about: costumes, publications, Kent exhibition in Moscow, and proposed gift to the USSR)
  - Rummel, Elizabeth, 1964-1965 (Reel 5230, Frame 472-476)
  - Rushia, Ector, 1970 (Reel 5230, Frame 477-482)
  - Russell, L. G., 1942 (Reel 5230, Frame 486-488)
  - Russell, Mrs., 1951 (Reel 5230, Frame 483-485)
  - Russell-Rutter Company, Inc., 1954 (Reel 5230, Frame 489-492)
  - Russian Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Reel 5230, Frame 493-573)
    (correspondence with Soviet friends about manned space flight, news of mutual friends, Cold War, travel plans (many letters in Russian, with English translations); bookplate samples from Nikiforov; see also: Nikiforov, Nikolai Alexeevich; Solov, Alyosha, Galya, and Nikiforov; Soviet Friends; and Zaborovsky, Frank)
  - Russian War Relief, 1941-1945 (Reel 5230, Frame 574-855)